Renzo Damian

Full Stack Developer

Lima, Peru renzo.damian.go@gmail.com

<u>Linkedin, Github,</u> <u>Portfolio</u>

Skills

Next.js

Typescript

JavaScript

React

Java

Python

Tailwind

HTML & CSS

SQL

Git

Hobbies

Biking

Soccer

Languages

English

Spanish

Profile

I'm a Full stack Developer with experience in maintaining legacy codebases, deploying new features, and ensuring quality assurance. I've developed responsive websites using modern web technologies and integrated APIs to monitor user actions and create new features. I collaborate with clients, business analysts, and teams of developers to improve components and workflows and love to learn new languages, tools and frameworks.

Employment History

Fullstack Java Developer, Bevertec, Lima

September 2022 - Present

- Created views and developed business logic using the MVC pattern with Grails Framework with JavaScript, HTML and Groovy
- Worked with Oracle database management to test and improve SQL queries
- Collaborating with the team in designing and implementing system architecture
- Add and refactor endpoints in the RESTful API using Spring Boot
- Work with QA using Jira tickets to ensure code quality, fix bugs and track changes and bitbucket to create and follow pull requests statuses

Web developer, Rebels 247, Lima

November 2021 - February 2022

- Worked with React and Vercel to deploy fast and lightweight websites to showcase a product or a company
- Created reusable Tailwind UI components in React to build similar pages faster
- Developed fixes and enhancements based on sprints reviews or meeting with clients on a weekly basis
- Sent user contact information to Active Campaign API for email marketing purposes
- Implemented Google analytics and Facebook pixel to track site and monitor user actions inside the website

Front end Developer, INET, Lima

October 2021 - November 2021

 Created services with typescript to connect with a RESTAPI to manage user input data

- Developed responsive website with SASS using the mobile-first principle and SEO fundamentals
- Built a real-time chat component with Firebase Realtime Database used in online conferences
- Interfaced with the client on a weekly basis, to improve and redesign components

Education

BS. Computer Science, Universidad Peruana de Ciencias Aplicadas

January 2018 — July 2023

Honor Scholarship awarded to the top 10% of students of each career on the 2021 - 01 semester.

Intermediate English Certificate, Instituto Cultural Peruano (ICPNA)

2015 - 2019

Listening B2 Proficiency Reading and Grammar B2 Proficiency

Internships

Front end Developer, UPC

July 2021 — September 2021

- Developed a responsive landing website for the Annual Marketing Congress at my university
- Wrote modern and maintainable code with HTML and CSS that will be used for future events
- Assigned specific tasks to a group of students to work on different components simultaneously of the web and API to improve workflow and collaboration
- Collaborated with a team of three using Git and GitHub

Courses & Certifications

Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design, Google @Corusera February 2022

Learn SQL Basics for Data Science, University of California, Davis @Coursera

November 2022